A Guide to the Lewis Gaylord Clark Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7503
Lewis Gaylord Clark Collection 1834-1867, n.d.
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7503
11 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit, 11 May 1964
Item Listing
- Letters
  - Lewis Gaylord Clark to Abraham Hart, 1834 Apr 12; ALS, 3 p.
    [Concerns recent purchase of
    Knickerbocker Magazine
    and planned improvements. Additional contributors announced. Requests publication at Hart's establishment, and welcomes literary contributions from Miss Leslie, a relative of Hart.]
  - Lewis Gaylord Clark to [Rufus] Babcock, 1838 Jan 23; ALS, 1 p.
    [Requests for publication two lectures given by Babcock to the Mercantile Library Association at Clinton Hall.]
  - Lewis Gaylord Clark to Charles Frederick Briggs, 1847 Sep 22; ALS, 2 p.
    [Mentions reading and enjoying a work of Briggs', "Scene at a Police-Court" in the
    Mirror
    . Mentions sending a note to [Charles ?] Dickens. ]
  - Lewis Gaylord Clark to Hamilton Fish, 1847 Dec 21; ALS, 2 p.
    [Appreciation of Fish's and Millard Fillmore's efforts and mentions St. Nicholas Festival. Mentions an amusing speech by Washington Irving. ]
  - Lewis Gaylord Clark to Curtis Guild, 1851 Oct [10]; ALS, 1 p.
    [Will return poetry to Guild as there is enough in magazine.]
  - Lewis Gaylord Clark to Noble Butler, 1852 Oct 25; ALS, 2 p.
    [Mentions trip with family to Lake Erie. Refers to extract of letter to Butler in Nov. issue of
    Harpers
    . ]
  - Lewis Gaylord Clark to Robert Conrad, [1867] Feb [26]; ALS, 1 p.
    [Praise for Charles Dickens. ]
  - Theo Hamilton to Becks, n. y. Jan 13; ALS, 1 p.
    [Mentions clippings and article from London [?]
    Times
  - Lewis Gaylord Clark to Harpers Magazine, n. y. May 15; ALS, 1 p.
    [Requests
    to send any books for notice in the July issue of the
  - Theo Hamilton to Becks, n. y. Dec. 8; ALS, 2 p.
    [Mentions enclosing a letter from "poor old Brown" and a new play by George Y. Holecest for Miss Rose Stake. ]
  - Lewis Gaylord Clark to Rufus Wilmot Griswold, n. d.; ALS, 1 p.
    [Social letter with questions about Griswold family. Mentions that his eldest daughter is very ill.]